My name's Conan Edogawa!
¡Soy Conan Edogawa!
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him.
Era Shinichi hasta que una organización me drogó y me encogí.
Although smaller, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
Aunque soy pequeño, soy un gran detective.
Today's case takes place in a high-rise building!
Hoy veremos un rascacielos. ¡Sus ascensores participan en un crimen!
Even when hidden behind double doors, there's always only one truth!
Aun con puertas, ¡solo hay una verdad!
The first end of the century in 100 years
El primer fin de siglo en 100 años.
When told to cry, I laughed instead
Cuando me dijeron que llorara, yo reí.
The first end of the century in a long, long time
El primer fin de siglo en mucho, mucho tiempo.
We're leaping into a wide open world
Nos lanzamos hacia un enorme mundo.
The things I tried to understand as a child
Las cosas que quería entender de niño
remain a mystery even as an adult
siguen siendo un misterio ahora que soy adulto.
I'm neither a hotshot nor especially great
No soy nadie importante ni nadie especial.
All I understand is the pounding of my heart
Lo único que comprendo es mi propio corazón,
It's neither an answer nor the truth
y eso no es una respuesta ni es la verdad.
The Elevator Murder Case.
"Asesinato en el ascensor".
Fitting Room
Vestidor
Come on, it's a holiday! Why's there so much traffic?!
¡Es un día libre! ¿Cómo hay tanto tránsito?
Are you sure it wouldn't have been faster by train?
¿No habría sido mejor ir en tren?
Being a model for Ashiya-san's clothing-- it's like a dream come true!
Ser modelo para la ropa de Ashiya es un sueño hecho realidad.
You're sure this is Ashiya Eiko, right?
¿Segura que es Eiko Ashiya?
You know that she's...
Ya sabes, esa mujer…
...One of the top fashion designers in Japan, right?
Es una de las mejores diseñadoras de Japón.
Wasn't Ashiya Eiko the one whose fashion show was cancelled recently?
¿Eiko Ashiya no es la que canceló un desfile hace poco?
A rival company announced a winter clothing line
Una compañía rival anunció una línea de invierno
very similar to the latest line that she was going to have at her show.
muy similar a la que ella iba a presentar en ese desfile.
So she had no choice but to cancel it.
No tuvo alternativa.
You sure know a lot about her!
Veo que sabe mucho de ella.
Don't tell me you're actually an Ashiya Eiko fan!
¿Acaso es fan de Eiko Ashiya?
I had no idea, Dad!
¡No lo sabía, papá!
Don't be silly! A detective must always expand his horizons
¡No seas tonta! Un detective debe saber de todo
to keep on top of what's going on in the world around him!
para poder conocer el mundo que lo rodea.
Sure...
Claro, claro…
Here it is!
Llegamos.
That's one big building...
Es un edificio enorme.
You're not going to be a model yourself, you know.
Usted no va a modelar.
I know that! You're really starting to get on my nerves!
¡Ya lo sé! ¡Empiezas a ponerme de mal humor!
Excuse me! My name's Mori Ran...
Disculpe, me llamo Ran Mori.
Ah, we've been expecting you.
Ah, la esperábamos.
The company president will be back soon. Please wait over there.
La presidenta llegará pronto. Espere por allí.
Sure!
Muchas gracias.
It certainly is quiet!
Es un sitio tranquilo.
Yes, today's a holiday, so there's no one else here.
Sí, es día festivo y casi no hay nadie.
I'm so sorry to keep you waiting, Ran-san!
-Siento haberte hecho esperar, Ran. -No importa.
Hey...
-Oye… -¿Qué?
Are big purses the latest style now?
¿Los bolsos grandes están de moda?
Her life revolves around all the up-and-coming fashions!
Las modas van y vienen.
I'm sure it'll catch on soon!
Pronto estaré al día.
I'm really sorry about that.
Cuánto lo siento.
This is my father and Conan Edogawa-kun.
Estos son mi padre y Conan Edogawa.
They absolutely insisted on coming with me...
Insistieron en acompañarme.
Mori Kogoro, at your service.
Kogoro Mori, a su servicio. Gracias por la oportunidad a mi hija.
Mori Kogoro? The famous detective?!
¿Kogoro Mori? ¿El famoso detective?
Oh, you've heard of me! What an honor this is!
Cielos, ¿me conoce? Es un honor.
These are a token of my admiration. Please accept them.
Una muestra de mi aprecio. Acéptelas.
Ashiya-sensei?
¿Señora Ashiya?
Sorry. Thank you.
Lo siento. Gracias.
Good morning.
Buenos días.
This is my secretary, Taniguchi Mika-san.
Esta es mi secretaria, Mika Taniguchi.
Nice to meet you.
Es un placer.
This is Mori Ran-san and her father, Kogoro-san.
Ran Mori, su padre, el señor Kogoro, y este es…
Conan Edogawa!
¡Conan Edogawa!
Right! Conan-kun!
Eso, Conan.
Sorry to call you here on a Sunday.
Siento hacerte venir un domingo.
That's okay. I'll just quit as soon as I can.
No importa. Así haré efectiva mi renuncia un día antes.
After all, I am being forced to work on weekends now.
Al fin y al cabo, ahora me obligan a trabajar los fines de semana.
Fine. Whatever you like.
Bien. Como quieras.
I'll just go put these flowers in my office and bring back the paperwork.
Iré a llevar las flores a mi despacho y traeré los papeles.
Please have a seat there with your father and Conan-kun while you wait.
Por favor, espera allí con tu papá y Conan.
Certainly!
De acuerdo.
Mika-san. Go to the 8th floor fitting room and get ready.
Mika, ve al vestidor del octavo piso y prepáralo todo.
See you shortly.
Hasta pronto.
Excuse me, but is that secretary quitting?
Disculpe, ¿esa secretaria se irá?
Yes. She's apparently already turned in her letter of resignation.
Sí. Ya entregó su renuncia.
They seem on such bad terms, but she still pushed the button for her.
Parecen enojadas, pero le llamó el ascensor.
Direct elevator to the 15th floor
Directo al piso 15
Direct elevator to the 8th floor (Stops at each floor coming down)
Al piso 8 (Para en todos)
Well, let's wait over here.
Bueno, esperemos.
But first I need to use the bathroom!
Primero debo ir al baño.
Same here!
-¡Yo también! -¡Pues vayan!
That feels much better!
Mucho mejor.
Did you both remember to wash your hands?
¿Se lavaron las manos?
Eda-san!
¡Señor Eda!
What is it?!
¿Qué sucede?
I called Mika-san's cell phone from my office, but she won't answer!
Llamé al celular de Mika, pero no responde.
Will you come look with me?
-¿Puede acompañarme? -Claro.
Why's she so worked up about someone not answering their phone?
¿Tanto se asusta porque no le responden?
That's strange.
Qué extraño.
The elevator Taniguchi-san used is stuck on the 8th floor.
El ascensor que usó Taniguchi está parado en el octavo.
Could something have happened to her?!
¿Le habrá pasado algo?
For now, let's take this elevator up and see for ourselves.
Subamos en este ascensor para comprobarlo.
What's the matter, Eiko-san?
¿Qué sucede, señora Eiko?
The secretary, Taniguchi Mika-san...
Es Mika Taniguchi.
Wait! There are footprints on the floor!
¡Espere! Hay huellas en el suelo.
Footprints...
Huellas.
It would seem they were made by dust from the emergency stairs!
Han de ser del polvo de las escaleras de emergencia.
A robber must've broke inside!
¡Debió ser un ladrón! ¡Entró, vio a Mika y la apuñaló!
It's almost like she knew this would happen to Taniguchi-san...
Es casi como si supiera que esto le ocurriría a Taniguchi.
Eda-san! Could you stop the door?
-Señor Eda, ¿puede parar las puertas? -Sí, claro.
I can't believe this...
No lo puedo creer.
These footprints...
Estas huellas…
Stabbed through the heart. Died almost instantly.
Le atravesaron el corazón. Murió en el acto.
Inspector!
¡Inspector!
These footprints are 26 centimeters in length.
Las huellas son de 26 centímetros.
26 centimeters, eh...
-De 26 centímetros, ¿eh? -Debe ser un hombre.
There's a blood stain on her shoulder...
Hay sangre en su hombro.
And what's this crease doing on the shoulder of her jacket?
¿Y esa arruga tan extraña en el brazo?
Would someone working in the overly conscious fashion industry
¿Alguien implicado en la industria de la moda
wear something with a crease like that?
se vestiría con algo tan arrugado?
But the strangest thing is that Taniguchi-san is lying on the ground
Pero lo más raro es que Taniguchi está en el suelo
facing away from the elevator.
hacia el lado opuesto al ascensor.
If she was stabbed as she got off the elevator,
Si la hubieran apuñalado al salir de él,
she would have collapsed inside it!
habría caído hacia su interior.
In which case, the killer must've purposely pulled her into the hallway.
Por lo que el asesino debió sacarla al pasillo
But why would they need to do that?!
Pero ¿por qué haría tal cosa?
You and Taniguchi-san were riding in different elevators, correct?
Taniguchi y usted subieron en ascensores diferentes, ¿verdad?
Yes. That elevator was the one I took.
Sí. Yo tomé ese.
The 15th floor?
¿El piso 15?
This goes non-stop to the 15th floor?
¿Este va hasta el piso 15 sin parar?
Yes, that's right.
Así es.
And this center elevator is the one Taniguchi Mika-san took?
Y el central es el que tomó Mika Taniguchi.
That one's non-stop to the 8th floor,
Ese no para hasta el octavo,
and then it can go floor-by-floor, all the way to the 15th floor.
y luego va piso a piso hasta el 15.
And then the one we took just now stops at the 8th floor,
Y el que tomamos sube hasta el octavo
then comes back down in single-floor increments...
y luego baja piso a piso.
That's correct.
Correcto.
Only two elevators can go to the 15th floor.
Solo dos ascensores suben al piso 15.
How much time passed from when Ashiya-san first got into the elevator
¿Cuánto pasó desde que la Srta. Ashiya subió al ascensor
until she returned here?
y luego volvió aquí?
Two minutes.
Dos minutos.
No, a little more than one minute, I think.
No, creo que algo más de un minuto.
A little under two minutes...
-Menos de dos minutos… -Inspector.
The emergency stairwell exit on the 1st floor was unlocked.
La escalera de emergencia del primer piso
When did you last do your rounds?
¿Cuándo hizo su ronda?
About 2 hours before the incident.
Dos horas antes del incidente.
I'm certain the door was locked then!
Y esa puerta estaba cerrada.
Did anyone enter or leave the building afterwards?
¿Alguien entró o salió del edificio tras eso?
Nobody except the company president.
Nadie excepto la presidenta.
Yes, I needed to check something.
Sí, necesitaba comprobar algo.
I arrived about an hour ago and was in my office for half an hour.
Llegué una hora antes y estuve media hora en mi despacho.
After that, I left to get some coffee.
Tras eso, fui por café.
I left through the main entrance, of course.
Salí por la entrada principal.
Inspector! I think Eiko-san is right--
¡Inspector! Creo que la señora Eiko tiene razón.
this was the work of a burglar breaking into the building!
Esto fue obra de un ladrón.
The killer unlocked the 1st floor emergency exit from the outside
El asesino entró por la salida de emergencia
and took the stairs to the 8th floor.
y subió hasta el octavo piso.
Then, just as he passed by the elevators...
Al pasar por los ascensores
...he ran into Taniguchi-san.
se encontró con Taniguchi.
He murdered her, then escaped back down the stairs.
La mató, huyó por las escaleras y posteriormente se fue.
Alright! Search the nearby vicinity immediately!
¡Bien! Revisen las inmediaciones.
Also, I'll need to take your fingerprints, Ashiya-san.
Y necesitaré sus huellas, señora Ashiya.
Are you implying that I'm the murderer?!
¿Es que soy sospechosa?
Nothing of the sort!
¡En absoluto!
It's to distinguish between the killer's fingerprints and yours!
Es para diferenciar sus huellas de las del asesino.
Besides, there's no way you could possibly have been the murderer!
Además, usted no pudo cometer el asesinato.
Why not?
¿Por qué no?
Are you stupid or something?!
¿Eres tonto?
Pay attention, now.
Presta atención.
Eiko-san and Taniguchi-san got in different elevators at the same time.
Eiko y Taniguchi subieron en ascensores diferentes a la vez.
Taniguchi-san arrived at the 8th floor
Taniguchi llegó al octavo y fue asesinada al abrirse las puertas.
Meanwhile, Eiko-san was on the 15th floor...
La señora Eiko estaba en el piso 15,
...and there was no elevator to take her to the 8th floor!
y no había ascensor para ir al octavo.
So how could she have killed Taniguchi-san?
¿Cómo pudo matar a Taniguchi?
But that doesn't clear her of all suspicion--
Eso no la libra de sospechas.
You're just a kid-- don't tell a pro how to do his job!
¡Eres un niño, no me digas cómo hacer mi trabajo!
That's no excuse for hitting him, Dad!
Pero no tienes que golpearlo.
But he just won't learn!
¡Es que no aprende!
What a lost cause! Can't depend on him at all!
¡No tiene remedio! No puedo contar con él.
Here goes!
-¡Bien! -¡Conan, ¿adónde vas?
Forget about him!
Déjalo.
If I'm right, the key to solving this case should be on the 15th floor!
Si tengo razón, la clave del caso está en el piso 15.
Wow! The company president's floor sure is nice!
Vaya, el piso de la presidenta es muy lujoso.
What fancy carpeting!
Una alfombra de lujo.
A flower petal?
¿Un pétalo?
Pollen...
Polen…
What's this?!
¿Y esto?
Tape marks!
¡Marcas de cinta!
President's Office
Presidencia
It's the same pollen.
Es el mismo polen.
Why?
¿Por qué?
Why was there a flower petal and pollen here?
¿Por qué hay un pétalo y polen aquí?
She wouldn't have passed by here if she went straight to her office...
No tenía que pasar por aquí para ir a su despacho.
Taniguchi-san was killed inside this elevator on the 8th floor.
Taniguchi fue asesinada en este ascensor en el octavo piso.
Ashiya Eiko-san was all by herself for just over a minute.
Eiko Ashiya se quedó sola por más de un minuto.
Taking the stairs to the 8th floor, killing her, and then coming back up
Bajar por las escaleras, matarla y subir de nuevo
would take at least 4 or 5 minutes.
le tomaría al menos 4 o 5 minutos.
Meaning that the question here is where exactly she was killed.
Así que la pregunta es dónde fue asesinada.
The way her body was lying on the ground...
Cómo estaba su cuerpo en el suelo…
The blood stain and the unnaturally crumpled part of her jacket...
La sangre del hombro y esa extraña arruga…
The flower petal lying on the floor...
El pétalo del suelo…
And the tape marks around the call button for the elevator
Y las marcas de cinta en el botón del ascensor de Taniguchi.
That's it! Now I get it!
¡Ya sé! ¡Ya lo entiendo!
This is an alibi trick involving elevators!
¡Es un truco usando los ascensores!
Taniguchi-san's murderer was indeed Ashiya Eiko!
Eiko Ashiya sí mató a Taniguchi.
No fingerprints at all?
¿No hay huellas?
Nope. There were none on the knife nor on the 1st floor emergency exit.
No. No había ni en el cuchillo ni en la salida de emergencia del primer piso.
Excuse me, Inspector. Would it be all right if I went home?
Disculpe, inspector, ¿podría irme a casa?
Of course. That should be enough for today...
Por supuesto. Ya hizo bastante por hoy.
Oh no! If she goes, she'll dispose of the evidence!
¡Rayos! ¡Si se va, se deshará de las pruebas!
I have no other choice! I'll have to use the old man again!
¡No tengo opción! ¡Usaré al viejo de nuevo!
Ran-san.
-Ran. -¿Sí?
Sorry, but can we do this another day?
-¿Podrías volver otro día? -¡Claro!
Well, I'll just be going now...
-Bueno, me voy. -La acompaño a la puerta.
...Which is what I would like to say, but we cannot allow you to leave.
Eso diría si no debiera impedir que se marche.
The reason being...
Y el motivo es…
...that you're the one who murdered Taniguchi Mika-san!
¡que usted asesinó a Mika Taniguchi!
Dad!
-¡Papá! -¿De qué hablas, Mori?
You were the one who just explained why she couldn't have done it!
Tú mismo dijiste que ella no podría haberlo hecho.
Yes, that I did.
No lo niego.
But that was a trick.
Pero era un truco.
A trick?!
¡¿Un truco?!
But first, allow me to explain those footprints in the 8th floor hallway.
Comenzaré explicando las huellas del octavo piso.
Have a seat, if you would.
Tomen asiento.
That was a ruse she concocted to make Taniguchi Mika-san's murder
Fue un montaje suyo
Try to remember what those footprints looked like.
Intenten recordar cómo eran las huellas.
Normally, someone would run away after committing a murder, correct?
Lo normal sería correr tras cometer un asesinato, ¿verdad?
This would cause the footprints to be far apart.
Las huellas deberían estar más separadas.
However, these footprints were made by someone walking
Pero esas huellas las hizo alguien caminando tanto al entrar como al salir.
I see. Now that you mention it, you're right...
Comprendo. Tienes razón.
Eiko-san.
Señora Eiko.
You entered the building an hour before the murder,
Entró al edificio una hora antes,
made the fake footprints,
dejó las huellas falsas,
and then unlocked the 1st floor emergency exit from the inside.
y desbloqueó la salida de emergencia del primer piso desde dentro.
After this, you hid the sneakers that don't fit you inside your large purse
Tras eso,
You came back 30 minutes later, after you had disposed of the sneakers.
Volvió 30 minutos después, tras deshacerse de ese calzado.
And then as we looked on,
Y como todos pudimos ver,
you headed for the elevator hall with Taniguchi Mika-san.
fue al ascensor con Mika Taniguchi.
You were the one who pressed the call button.
Usted presionó el botón de llamada.
The reason being that you needed her to use the center elevator
Lo hizo porque necesitaba que usara el ascensor central
instead of the one that was nearest to her.
en lugar del más cercano a ella.
Inside the elevator, you started dialing her number on your cell phone.
Dentro del ascensor marcó su número en su celular.
After getting off on the 15th floor, you pressed the dial button.
Tras bajar en el piso 15, presionó el botón de llamada.
It's hard for cell phones to connect while inside elevators, you see.
La cobertura falla en los ascensores.
You told Taniguchi-san to come to the 15th floor right away.
Le dijo a Taniguchi que fuera al piso 15 de inmediato.
Meanwhile, you taped a coin to the call button on the 15th floor.
Y puso una moneda en el botón de llamada en el piso 15.
You did this to make sure the elevator doors wouldn't close
Así evitó que las puertas del ascensor se cerraran mientras la mataba.
Hold on!
¡Un momento!
Mori-kun! The victim was found dead on the 8th floor!
¡Mori, la víctima estaba en el piso 8!
Now we come to the main point of the trick.
Ahora llegamos al punto clave del truco.
Didn't you find the direction she was lying strange?
¿No les parecía rara la postura de Taniguchi?
If she had been stabbed by someone as she was getting off the elevator,
De haber sido apuñada al salir del ascensor,
she would have fallen back into it.
habría caído dentro de él.
But she was lying outside of the elevator, facing away from it.
Pero estaba afuera, como cayendo hacia atrás de él.
Now that you mention it...
Ahora que lo dices…
Eiko-san stabbed Taniguchi-san on the 15th floor,
Eiko apuñaló a Taniguchi en el piso 15,
got behind her, and then turned her in the direction of the hallway.
se puso tras ella y la giró hacia el pasillo.
Then she pressed the button for the 8th floor
Luego presionó el botón al octavo piso
and removed the tape from the call button.
y quitó la cinta del botón.
She then propped Taniguchi-san up in a sitting position
Dejó a Taniguchi en postura sentada
and sent her down to the 8th floor.
y la envió al octavo piso.
I can't believe she would do such a thing...
Me cuesta creerlo…
There were two keys to unraveling the mystery behind this alibi trick.
Había dos claves para develar el misterio.
The first was the crease on the shoulder of Taniguchi-san's jacket.
La primera era la arruga de la chaqueta de Taniguchi.
It was created when the jacket was caught between the elevator doors.
La crearon las puertas del ascensor al atraparla.
The second key was in the flower petal and pollen left on the carpet
La segunda clave eran el pétalo y el polen del alfombrado,
when Eiko-san put the bouquet on the floor
pues la señora Eiko puso el ramo en el suelo para que no le estorbara.
That's an interesting story.
Una historia interesante.
But it's nothing but a theory.
Pero no es más que una teoría.
Besides, if Taniguchi-san rode the 8th floor elevator a second time,
Además, si Taniguchi hubiera tomado ese ascensor una segunda vez,
her fingerprint should have been on the 8th floor call button.
su huella se encontraría en el botón de llamada del octavo.
Well, Inspector?
¿Y bien, inspector?
Any fingerprints on the call button?
¿Había huellas en el botón?
No. No fingerprints at all.
No. No había ninguna.
Sorry, Mori-san. Taniguchi-san didn't go to the 15th floor.
Lo siento, señor Mori. Taniguchi no subió al piso 15.
Your theory has been disproved!
Su teoría queda descartada.
Indeed. Because you removed her fingerprint yourself.
Cierto. Porque usted eliminó la huella.
Truly stupendous execution, it was.
Un trabajo encomiable.
In order to close the elevator doors, you pressed the call button
Para cerrar las puertas, presionó el botón
and then removed her fingerprint by wiping it off.
y quitó la huella frotándola.
Wait a minute! Does that mean there's no proof?!
¡Un momento! Entonces, ¿no hay pruebas?
Oh, there's proof all right.
Sí que hay una.
Inside Eiko-san's purse!
En el bolso de la señora Eiko.
What kind of proof?!
¿Qué clase de prueba?
The bloody gloves she used when committing the murder.
Los guantes ensangrentados por el crimen.
Time-wise, she shouldn't have been able to dispose of them.
No ha podido tener tiempo de deshacerse de ellos.
And she couldn't dare hide them inside the building.
Y no los ocultaría dentro del edificio.
You were more than confident about your elevator alibi trick.
Confiaba demasiado en su truco del ascensor.
In other words, the only possibility is that the bloodied gloves
Es decir, que la única opción
The one who stole your design and sold it to that rival company...
La que le robó sus diseños y se los vendió a su rival
...was Taniguchi Mika-san, wasn't it?
fue Mika Taniguchi, ¿verdad?
You're right. The evidence is here, too.
Cierto. Y la prueba está aquí.
But I did it because she had betrayed me.
Pero lo hice porque me traicionó.
She said she didn't care if I went to the police
Le daba igual que la denunciara,
because after canceling my fashion show,
porque tras cancelar mi desfile,
doing so would only damage the Ashiya Eiko brand name even more.
ir a la policía solo dañaría más el nombre de Eiko Ashiya.
Letter of Resignation
Carta de renuncia
Then she tried to quit the company.
Entonces, intentó renunciar.
I decided to kill her while she was still with the company.
Decidí matarla antes de que se fuera.
And that was today...
Y eso fue hoy…
When I heard your father was the famous detective Mori Kogoro-san,
Cuando oí que tu papá era
I didn't know what to do.
no sabía qué hacer.
But I didn't have a change of heart.
Pero no pude cambiar de idea.
Just my imagination
Solo mi imaginación.
Playing with threads around my finger while drinking lukewarm tea
Juego con un hilo entre mis dedos mientras me tomo un té caliente.
Let's walk lightly to the bossa nova rhythm
Caminemos ligeros al ritmo de la bossa nova.
The puzzle pieces are in my hands
Las piezas del rompecabezas están en mis manos.
That's right...
Así es…
I was in the same place last week but with different clothes
La semana pasada estaba en el mismo lugar pero con otra ropa.
Step by step, there's no reason to be anxious
Paso a paso, no hay por qué ponerse nerviosos.
Case by case, I don't care if you laugh
Caso a caso, no me importa que te rías.
Beyond the countless days, she's waiting for me
Más allá de los innumerables días, ella me espera.
Ran-san.
Ran.
You may not believe me,
Tal vez no me creas,
but I was telling the truth when I told you why I wanted you as a model.
pero dije la verdad con lo de quererte como modelo.
I wanted someone with a healthy mind and body such as yourself
Quería que alguien tan equilibrada como tú
to wear Ashiya Eiko clothing.
vistiera la ropa de Eiko Ashiya.
I'm so sorry, Ran-neechan...
Lo siento, Ran.
You almost had your chance to be a model...
Era tu oportunidad de ser modelo.
No, that's okay.
No, está bien.
Huh? Come to think of it, where's Dad?
¿Eh? Es verdad, ¿dónde está papá?
Whoops! I left him there, asleep!
¡Diablos! ¡Lo dejé allí durmiendo!
It looks like this case has taken its toll on him...
Parece que este caso lo afectó mucho.
After all, he's a fan of Ashiya Eiko-san, and he just exposed her crime!
Era fan de Eiko Ashiya y tuvo que exponer su crimen.
If he found out I was the one who exposed her crime, he'd murder me!
Si descubre que la expuse yo, me matará a mí.
Mitsuhiko!
¡Mitsuhiko!
I've figured it out! You're the ghost!
¡Lo descubrí! ¡Tú eres el fantasma!
On the next Conan--
Próximamente:
The Haunted House Murder.
"Asesinato en la casa embrujada".
Next Conan's Hint:
Próxima pista de Conan:
Eerie basement.
Sótano lúgubre.